A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Art Reference Files FA522
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Art Files, 2; 5.41 Cubic Feet 13 letter-size document boxes and 1 legal-size document box
  - Art Curators' Files, 1935-2006; 2
    - Sotheby's and Christie's Appraisals, 1983, 1993-1994, 1999-2002 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      Christie's appraisal of Asian art and antiquities at Room 5600, December 1994; Sotheby's appraisal of Fine Art at Room 5600, August 1994; Paintings, drawings, and prints at 834 Fifth Avenue and Kent House, undated; Tobacco Leaf porcelain, Sotheby's appraisal (Deborah Gage) and photos, April 1993; Meissen birds and porcelain, and photos of display cases, 834 Fifth Avenue, appraisal circa 1979. Also includes invoice for LSR's acquisition of Buddha Sakyamuni, Sotheby's sale, March 21, 2002.
    - Leith Talamo Memos, 1998-2002 (Box 5, Folder 56)
      Outgoing memos from curator Leith Talamo on LSR art collection, cataloguing, and appraisals; and some incoming memos from Ellen R.C. Pomeroy. Includes 1999 biographical sketch of Leith Talamo and her LSR-related art duties; 3 polaroids of 8 art works on paper by Zorach ("lesser" Zorachs), donated to Buffalo Bill Historical Society Art Sale, September 2002; auction of Egyptian turquoise faience Baboon figure, November 2002. File also includes notes on the filing system for LSR's art files.
    - Collections (General), 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 57)
      List of Paul Maze works in LSR's collection, plus correspondence concerning Christie's sale of Paul Maze works, offered by his widow, 1998; List of kinetic, sound-, and other sculptures by Bertoia, Lassaw, Rickey, etc. File includes 10 Polaroid photos of some of these sculptures.
    - 834 Fifth Avenue - Current, 1984-2004 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      Casts of Stephanie Klein, "Flying Rabbit," sculpture, 2003-2004; Ozenfant, "Pipe Book," loan inquiry; Yvonne Force correspondence; purchase of Buddha Aksobhya figure, 1998; Paul Maze collector; Albert Murray brochure; George Rickey, "Space Churn" purchase, 1987; NAR portrait, 1985; copy of Cezanne, "Jug and Fruit on Table"; Zorach Animal Sculpture exhibit, Zabriskie Gallery, 2001-2002; inventory of paintings at 834 Fifth Ave by location, plus Polaroid photos; Audubon books.
    - 834 Fifth Avenue - Current, 1984-2004 (Box 5, Folder 58A)
      Restricted - Living Rockefeller Family - Restricted for Life
    - Kent House, 1986-2002 (Box 5, Folder 59)
      General file: appraisals of furnishings and decorative art, fine art, and Chinese porcelains (1998) at the Japanese Shrine and Kent House; Lassaw sculpture at Kykuit; photos of Soldwedel watecolors; Frederick Rondel, "Statue of Liberty Celebration, 1886" (color transparency); Toulouse-Lautrec lithograph.
    - Echo Acre, 1987-2001 (Box 5, Folder 60)
      Undated Appraisal of paintings at Echo Acre; Inventory of LSR's office suite, Woodstock, 1987; Inventory of Art at the Woodstock Inn, 1989; Echo Acre: History of Ownership, Construction, and Alteration, 1995.
    - Echo Acre - Sotheby's Appraisal, 2001 June 14 (Box 5, Folder 61)
      Also includes appraisal of LSR's offices in Woodstock, VT.
    - JY Ranch - Art Purchases and Gifts, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Christie's Appraisal - Furniture, 1994 August 9 (Box 5, Folder 63)
      Appraisal of European Furniture and auction proposal.
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Sotheby's Appraisal, 1994 August 22 (Box 5, Folder 64)
      Tibetan, Chinese, Egyptian, and other works of art.
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Sotheby's Appraisal, 1995 January 20 (Box 5, Folder 65)
      Fine art.
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Sotheby's Appraisals, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 66)
      Chinese, Tibetan, Egyptian, and Fine Art.
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Sotheby's Appraisals, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 66A)
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Christie's Appraisals, 1994, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 67)
      Fair market value and insurance appraisals. Includes Southeast Asian and Asian Art, Decorative Objects, Fine Art, December 2, 1994; Fine Art, Native American Art, and Indigenous Art, February 28, 2001.
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Christie's Appraisals, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 67A)
    - LSR Office, Room 5600 - Ralph M. Chait Appraisal, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 68)
      Chinese art and sculpture.
    - Furniture, 1976-1977, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 69)
      Charles Uht photos of furniture at 834 Fifth Avenue, circa 1970s; miscellaneous furniture purchases and photos.
    - 834 Fifth Avenue - Antique Furniture Appraisal, 1965 June 1 - 1967 (Box 5, Folder 70)
      Appraisal by J. A. Lloyd Hyde, and 1967 revision and supplement.
    - Kent House - Antique Furniture, China, and Ornaments Appraisal, 1956 November 5 - 1967 June 1 (Box 5, Folder 71)
      Furniture appraisal by J. A. Lloyd Hyde, and 1967 revision; undated listing of China and ornaments.
    - Porcelain (General), 1940-1976 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      Copies of catalogue cards for various china sets acquired by purchase, gift, or bequest.
    - Silver (General), 1935, 1945-1948, 1972-1988 (Box 6, Folder 73)
      Inventories and invoices. Also includes packing lists and inventories for linens, china, and glass, 1940s.
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller Estate - LSR Selections, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 74)
      Porcelains, Paintings, Household Items (Furniture, Silver, China, etc.), Jewelry. Decriptions include photos and provenance information. Inventory pages removed from three-ring binder.
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller Estate - LSR Selections, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 74A)
    - Repairs and Loans, 1980, 1989-2002 (Box 6, Folder 75)
      Cleaning and restoration work on carpets, fan, Himalayan bronzes; framing; and porcelain repairs. Loan of Zorach sculptures; Ozenfant "Livre, Pipe" painting (photos made for [Francoise] Ducros); request for study of Rockefeller family portraiture. Also includes two Daniel Delamare certificates for copies of Henri Rousseau and Paul Gauguin paintings, 1989.
      Redacted originals.
    - Repairs and Loans, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 75A)
      Restricted - Living Rockefeller Family - Restricted for Life.
    - Missing Items, 1979-2002 (Box 6, Folder 76)
      Including antique chairs; Famile Noire vases and jars.
    - Missing Items, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 76A)
    - Audubon Prints, 1986-2001 (Box 6, Folder 77)
      Includes Christie's appraisals, 1996 and 2001.
    - Harry Bertoia (Box 6, Folder 78)
      Catalogue card, negative, and Uht photograph of "Sound Sculpture," which MFR purchased in 1969.
    - Paul Maze, 1958-1979, 1996-2003 (Box 6, Folder 79)
      Exhibit catalogues, 1958-1973; 1979 obituary; photos of Maze in his studio and correspondence with his wife Jesse; autograph letter, 1971; lists of artworks and values; correspondence with collectors, 1997-2001. Includes 6 black and white photos of Maze paintings in LSR's collection.
    - Amedeo Modigliani, 1997, 1999, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 80)
      Correspondence concerning authenticity of painting, Young Woman with Black Hair, which had been declared a forgery; certificate by Marc Restellini; new appraisal. File includes black and white photo of the painting.
    - Modigliani, "Young Woman with Black Hair" - Authentication and Sale, 1999-2012 (Box 6, Folder 81)
      Correspondence of LSR's associates and executors with the Rockefeller Archive Center and Sotheby's, concerning documentation and authentication of the painting, and its anticipated sale on behalf of the LSR Fund. File includes the catalogue for Bonhams' Impressionist and Modern Art sale, February 7, 2012. This file was sent to the Rockefeller Archive Center by Ellen R.C. Pomeroy, Director of the LSR Fund in 2012, following Bonham's sale of the painting. This file has been added to LSR's Art Reference Files, as it is closely related to the Modigliani file in this series.
    - Charles and Maurice Prendergast, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 82)
      Works belonging to LSR and MFR included in catalogue raisonne; 4 color slides.
    - Paul Resika, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 83)
      Invoice for paintings purchased by Mary French Rockefeller in December 1992.
    - Toulouse-Lautrec, Au Cafe, 1950, 1954-1958 (Box 7, Folder 84)
      Correspondence and research concerning the authenticity of the watercolor painting, which Abby Aldrich Rockefeller had purchased from the Downtown Gallery in 1928, but which had recently been deemed a forgery.
    - Toulouse-Lautrec - Acquisitions, 1971, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 85)
      Two lithographs: Aristide Bruant dans Son Cabaret, gift from NAR to LSR, 1971; May Milton, purchased for LSR at Christie's November 11, 1977, sale.
    - Toulouse-Lautrec - Sotheby's Appraisal and Sale (1999), 1996-2000 (Box 7, Folder 86)
      Six lithographs offered at Sotheby's November 4-6, 1999, auction.
    - William Zorach, 1958-1959, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 87)
      American Artist article on Zorach watercolors, with cover letter from Zorach, 1958; Yosemite catalogue, Zabriskie Gallery, January-February 1979, with note attached: pencil drawing "Valley of Bright Waters" 1920 was given to LSR by MFR, 1979.
    - Exhibition Catalogues, 1956-1985 (Box 7, Folder 88)
      Various sales and exhibition catalogues, including some LSR loans and acquisitions. Harold Sterner, Jean Venitien, Trafford Klots, William Bradford, Paul Resika.
    - Catalogues - Sculpture, 1957-1982 (Box 7, Folder 89)
      Includes Fine Arts Associates; George Rickey; Masayuki Nagare; and Hirschl and Adler Galleries, American Sculpture 1810-1940.
    - Sculptures, 1959-1991 (Box 7, Folder 90)
      Correspondence, photos, catalogues. Includes George Rickey exhibit, 1959; William Zorach purchase, 1961; Paul Resika purchase, 1991; Rod Kagan, photos, 1991; Art of Trailside Galleries, 1985-1986; National Heritage Collectors Society catalogue; James Earle Fraser, End of the Trail (casts), undated.
    - Sculptures, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 90A)
    - Dallin, Appeal to the Great Spirit, 1985, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      File consists of two items: Sotheby's sale catalogue, Important American 18th, 19th, and 20th Century Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture, 1985 May 30 (item 122); memo from Leith Talamo to Wes Frye, 2001, concerning casts of the sculpture.
    - Art Donations - General, 1991-2002 (Box 7, Folder 92)
      Including Buffalo Bill Historical Center (Dallin, "Appeal to the Great Spirit," and contribution of 8 Zorach works on paper for Art Sale, 2001-2002); National Geographic Society (Jefferys Atlas, 2001); Helicopter Museum (James Dietz painting of Boeing Vertol helicopter, 1997); Whitney Museum, 1991-2000; YWCA.
    - Donations to Charities, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 93)
      Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) Thrift Shop, Lenox Hill Neighborhood House, YWCA (clipping).
    - Gifts to Family, 1956, 1994-2003 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      Includes information on Thomas Gainsborough portrait of Miss Juliet Mott, 1956; also includes still image of Diego Rivera's 1932 portrait sketch of Abby Rockefeller Milton.
    - Gifts to Family, 1956, 1994-2003 (Box 8, Folder 94A)
    - Gifts to Friends, 1983, 1995-2003 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Arkansas Arts Center, 1988, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 96)
      Donation of prints and drawings.
    - Laurance S. Rockefeller Fund, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 97)
      Donation of paintings by Monet, Braque, Toulouse-Lautrec.
    - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - General, 1985-2003 (Box 8, Folder 98)
      Donation of Cezanne, "Jug and Fruits on a Table," 1985; LSR donations, 1999; framing of Audubon prints; correspondence with painter Lonna Lord Davis; Patient Art Shows; Art Committee (chaired by Leith Talamo), renovations and decorating; unflattering watercolor portrait of Mr. Sloan (including polaroid print); Mary French Rockefeller chapel at MSKCC.
    - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Picasso Tapestries, 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 99)
      Memo concerning restoration and possible sale of 3 Picasso tapestries LSR had donated to MSKCC in 1982.
    - Society of Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Art Committee, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 100)
      Budget issues concerning MSKCC art collection purchases.
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund - Picasso Tapestries, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 101)
      Gift of two Picasso tapestries to the Rockefeller Brothers Fund, and one tapestry (at Kykuit) to the National Trust for Historic Preservation.
    - San Antonio Museum of Art, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 102)
      Gift of paintings by Diego Rivera, Pedro Friedeberg, and Jean Charlot.
    - Smithsonian Institution, National Museum of African Art, 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 103)
      Gift of paintings, sculpture, and decorative art.
    - Colonial Williamsburg (Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Center), 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 104)
      Gift of works by Victor Gatto, Jay Robinson, Obin, and Alix Roy.
    - Woodstock (Marsh-Billings-Rockefeller National Historical Park), 2002, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 105)
      Donation of books.
    - Art Purchases, Gifts, and Sales - General, 1955-2006 (Box 8, Folder 106)
      Includes actions by LSR and MFR. File includes list of art donations, 1995-1996; Laura Chasin, LSR Family Art Sale catalogue, 2005 (for benefit of Public Conversations Project); P.C. Loo and Sons, Certificates of Antiquity for two 18th-century gilt bronze Buddhas (items CX-13, HSX-43), 1985; Moran paintings and other art at Woodstock Mansion and Billings Farm, 1988-1994; LSR fine art purchases, 1986; Memo and bid for Rodin, The Thinker, 1976; Antique Porcelain Company, purchase of Remington, Coming Through the Rye bronze, and various porcelain pieces, 1976; purchase of Demuth, Red Gladioli, from Winthrop Rockefeller estate, 1975; Fine Arts reports for 1975 and 1977; Thomas Devine memo to his successor Virginia Brown, 1968, on LSR's and MFR's art card catalogue; George Rickey, Vine mobile, 1959; Cezanne, Jug and Fruits on a Table, 1955, memo and photo.
    - Art Purchases (2 folders), 1975-1995 (Box 9, Folder 107-108)
      Artwork by various artists, including: (Folder 107) Larry Rivers, Washington Crossing the Delaware; Vincente Vuides; Leroy Neiman, Skiing (includes photo and transparency); J.G. Tyler, River Boat America, and sale catalogue (Sotheby Parke Bernet no. 3749, American 18th, 19th and 20th Century Paintings, April 17, 1975); and (Folder 108) Patrick Farrow sculpture; F. Cowles, Moonscape; Milford Zornes; Lloyd Sexton; tin whirligig and ivory necklaces, Sotheby's, 1983; William Zorach; Anna Mary Robertson (Grandma) Moses; Thomas Hart Benton, Hayfield and sale catalogue (Sotheby Parke Bernet no. 4290, American 19th and 20th Century Paintings, October 25, 1979).
    - Art Purchases, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 108A)
    - Art Purchases, Loans, and Gifts - Mary French Rockefeller, 1950-1968, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 109)
      Invoices for various artworks purchased by MFR, 1950s-1960s; LSR purchases from Stuart and Turner, 1957; Gautama Buddha, Doris Wiener Gallery, 1967; correspondence concerning YWCA and Japanese and Korean artists; Kiyoshi Saito prints; MFR purchases from estate of Mary Billings French, 1952; loan to Charles Prendergast exhibit and catalogue, 1968; Paul Resika paintings, 1992, 1994. File also includes letter from Edith Halpert, 1950, concerning provenance of Toulouse-Lautrec watercolor, Au Cafe; and Carol Uht condition report, 1955, on Cezanne, Jug and Fruits, painting.
    - Art Purchases - Galerie Daniel Delamare, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - Auction Bids, 1978-1984 (Box 9, Folder 111)
      General file; mainly unsuccessful bids. File incudes photo of Bierstadt, "Cathedral Rock, Yosemite."
    - Auction Sales -Christie's, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 112)
      Sale of Chinese low table and two English chairs, 1995; sale of jewelry and Buddha Sakyamuni, and estimated overcharges, 1998.
    - Auction Sales - Sotheby's (2 folders), 1990-2002 (Box 9, Folder 113-114)
      Sales of Famille Noire porcelain, 1990-1991; Tobacco Leaf and Meissen porcelain, 1998-1999. Arrangements for sale of Pierre Bonnard, Robe a Carreaux, 1999, and Foujita, Mon Portrait no. 3 (on behalf of Princeton); sale of prints by Toulouse-Lautrec and Mary Cassatt (Woman Bathing), at Sotheby's 19th and 20th Century Prints (sale 7367), 1999 November 4-5. Sale of Egyptian faience Baboon at Sotheby's Antiquities sale, December 11, 2002, on behalf of the LSR Fund.
    - Art Deaccessions (3 folders), 1973-2003 (Box 10, Folder 115-117)
      Folder 115: Purchases and sales or gifts of art, including: Domenico Veneziano, Portrait of Michele Olivieri; Hans Hoffman, Variations on a Theme in Green (includes transparency); gifts to Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (including Cezanne, Jug and Fruits on a Table, appraisal and photo, 1985-1986); View of Old Nassau Hall, Princeton, gift to Brooke Astor; Circle of Sir Joshua Reynolds, Portrait of a Woman," from Nelson A. Rockefeller estate; Cezanne, The Large Bathers, and Matisse, Odalisque a la Jupe de Tulle (lithographs); undated inventory of porcelain china services.
      Folder 116 - 1994-1995: MFR purchase of Resika, Blue Fayence. Gift of Washo baskets to Woodstock Foundation; gift of Monet, "Mme Monet in Her Garden," and of Braque, "Landscape," to LSR Fund; gifts to Brooke Astor; gifts of Buddhas to Robert Thurman, Joan Halifax, Richard Baker; Egyptian Bronze Cat to Courtney Ross.
      Folder 117 - 1996-2003: (1996) Winslow Homer watercolor, "Shark Fishing," to MSKCC; Toulouse-Lautrec, "Au Cafe," to LSR Fund; Paul Maze pastels to Douglas Warner and MSKCC; Currier and Ives, "Sunnyside" print to Brooke Astor; Wieghorst, "Sioux Warrior." (1997) Buddhas to Yvonne Force and Louis Marx; "Moonscape," by Fleur Cowles; Scholar's Rock; Daumier and Degas drawings to the Arkansas Arts Center; Fujita, "Mon Portrait No. 3," to Princeton University; Ozenfant, "Pipe, Livre" exhibit request. (1998) Picasso tapestries to Rockefeller Brothers Fund; donations to MSKCC; W.J. Bennett, West Point engraving (with transparency) (purchased 1988).
    - Art Deaccessions, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 117A)
    - Asian Art (2 folders), 1963, 1973-1998, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 118-119)
      Purchases of Buddhas and other figurines, 1976-1998; Japanese "rabbits and birds" screen, 1975; repairs to Kang H'si vase, 1988; appraisal of walking Buddha, 1974; Ashkenazie appraisal of Yang Kuei-fei carving, 1992; Sotheby's and Christie's sale catalogues, 1980-1981, 1986. Includes some still images.
    - Asian Art - Ralph M. Chait Galleries, 1990s? (Box 10, Folder 120)
      Item descriptions of: Large Carved Black Stone Figure and Animal (item no. 1317); Unusual Gilded Porcelain Figure of Amitabha Buddha, dated 1771 AD (item no. 16186); Small Grey Stone "Meditation Rock"; Unusual Pair of small Canton enamel figures of recumbent rabbits (item no. 16333; includes color transparency). Also includes descripion of a Khmer bronze guiding ring for a palanquin offered by J.J. Klejman. Item no. 1317 was given to Brooke Astor, 1995; and the Meditation Rock was given to Courtney Ross in 1997.
    - Native American Art - General, 1971-2000 (Box 10, Folder 121)
      Purchases, handling and disposition, insurance scheduling, and appraisal. Includes list of jewelry purchased in consultation with Frederick Dockstater, 1971; David Vernon memorial card, and letter from Betty Mitchell to Mary French Rockefeller, 1973; purchase of blankets, 1978; transport of pottery, baskets, and textiles to Wyoming, 1982-1983; purchase of Wieghorst, Sioux Warrior, from Leonard Firestone, 1994; chief's blanket given to President Clinton, 1995; appraisal of LSR's Native American Art, 2000. Includes photograph of San Ildefonso blackware pot, 1990.
    - Native American and Western Art - Invoices, 1976-1995 (Box 10, Folder 122)
      Gallery invoices for blankets, rugs, baskets, jewelry, paintings, pottery. Includes: Sotheby's, 1980-1981; Main Trail Galleries, 1982-1984; Tanner Productions (Rick Tanner), 1981-1983; Gallery 10, 1980-1981; Trailside Galleries, 1976-1993. Also documents on polar bear carving by Inuit artist Egesiak Simionie, gift of Hanne and Maurice Strong, 1994.
    - Navajo Blankets and Rugs, 1975-1995 (Box 11, Folder 123)
      Includes still images; and estimate for conservation treatment of Native American wall hanging, 1995.
    - Washoe Baskets, 1971, 1993-1995 (Box 11, Folder 124)
      Baskets purchased at Parke-Bernet sale, 1971 November 19, on recommendation of Frederick Dockstader. File includes purchase memo, invoice, and catalogue cards; Harmer Johnson appraisal, 1994; and correspondence concerning LSR's donation of three baskets (including two by Dat-So-La-Lee) to the Woodstock Foundation in 1994 and their 1995 sale on behalf of the foundation.
    - Sotheby's "Fine American Indian Art", 1981 October 23 (Box 11, Folder 125)
      LSR bids and purchases. Sale number 4708Y.
    - Sotheby's "Fine American Indian Art", 1982 April 24 (Box 11, Folder 126)
      LSR purchases. Sale number 4842Y.
    - Sotheby's "Fine American Indian, African and Oceanic Art", 1982 October 23 (Box 11, Folder 127)
      LSR purchases of Native American baskets, pottery, and beadwork.
    - Sotheby's "Fine American Indian Art", 1983 October 22 and 24 (Box 11, Folder 128)
      LSR purchases.
    - Sotheby's "Fine American Indian Art", 1984 October 25-26 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Silver Appraisal - 834 Fifth Avenue and Kent House, 1967 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 130-131)
      Two copies of the appraisal by James A. Lloyd Hyde. The copy in folder 130 includes penciled notations showing the changes in value. The copy in folder 131 incorporates the updated valuations.
    - Silver Appraisal - 834 Fifth Avenue and Tarrytown (Kent House), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 132)
      Appraisal lists values for 1967 and 1970.
    - Silver Appraisal - James Robinson - 834 Fifth Avenue and Kent House, 1980 December (Box 11, Folder 133-134)
      Two copies. The first copy (in folder 133) includes some markings and insertions. The second copy (in folder 134) includes a cover letter from Ellen R.C. Pomeroy to Kendall Lutkins, 1997 September 5.
    - Silver Appraisal - James Robinson - 834 Fifth Avenue and Kent House, 1999 March 31 (Box 12, Folder 135)
    - Porcelains - General, 1973-1997 (Box 12, Folder 136)
      Correspondence mainly with the Antique Porcelain Company concerning Meissen birds and other pieces - offers, purchases, and repairs; lawsuit over breakages. Also includes sale of Chinese porcelain pieces originally from JDR Jr.'s collection.
    - Porcelains - Photographs (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 137-138)
      Black and white 8"x10" photographs by Charles Uht of items from LSR's porcelain collection. Includes Meissen, Chinese, and other European porcelain china and figurines. Also includes some glassware. Color 8"x10" transparency of Meissen bantam cock and hen; accordion-folded photo board showing display of Meissen birds and china in cabinet at 834 Fifth Ave (color photos, cut and glued to board).
    - Porcelains - Bills of Sale and Supporting Documents (2 folders), 1975-1985 (Box 12, Folder 139-140)
    - Porcelains - Bills of Sale and Catalogues, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Porcelains - Bills of Sale and Catalogues (2 folders), 1980-1981, 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 142-143)
    - Tobacco Leaf Porcelains (2 folders), 1974-1979, 1988-1996 (Box 13, Folder 144-145)
    - Famille Noire Porcelains, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 146)
      Seven pieces included in Sotheby's sale of November 27, 1990.
    - Jewelry - General, 1948-1986, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 147)
      Insurance schedules; Schlumberger exhibit; jewelry selections from Martha Baird Rockefeller estate, 1971, and Lucy Truman Aldrich estate, 1956; letter from JDR Jr. to his children concerning his apportionment among them of jewelry from Abby Aldrich Rockefeller estate, 1948.
    - Jewelry - General, 1948-1986, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 147A)